

Leonardo Calderon J.

Software Engineer STEM Professor

<u>leocjj.tech/</u> +573165237608

PROFILE

Software Engineer with experience also as a Project Manager and STEM Professor, onsite and remotely, goal-oriented, with skills and strengths to enhance teams, processes, and businesses.

Interested in high-level language applications especially Python, Data Analysis and become a Machine Learning expert and Data Scientist.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- VS Code, Jupyter, PyCharm.
- C, Python, Numpy, Pandas, R.
- HTML, Javascript, CSS, PHP, AJAX, Flask, Django.
- AWS Lambda, API Gateway, S3.
- Shell, Git/GitHub.
- REST API, MySQL.
- MS Sharepoint, Excel, Project.
- Linux, Windows, Arduino, Raspberry.
- Mathematics, Statistics, Physics.
- Entrepreneurship.
- Investment projects formulation and evaluation.
- Financial and stock market fundamentals.

CORE STRENGTHS

- Leadership
- Change management
- Problem Solver
- Teamwork
- Strategic planning
- Process management
- Critical thinking
- Agile-Scrum focus

PROFESSIONAL HISTORY

Pfizer - Warner Lambert Junior engineer 2003-2007

• Created a Commissioning & Qualification (C&Q) program.

Baxter Senior engineer 2007-2015

- Achieved status as a regional auditor and consultant.
- Finished a 2-years project as Software validation lead.

Research Software Engineer, Univalle

2018

• Researched science projects with Arduino, Python, and NumPy.

Software Engineer Full Stack, RedSST.com

2019

2020

• Implemented HTML5, CCS, JS, PHP, AJAX, Python, and MySQL.

Software Engineer IoT with Google Cloud and Python

Veos Technology

- Tested MQTT protocol for IoT telemetry using Google Cloud Platform.
- Reduced communication package size consumption by 80%.

Software Engineer Backend AWS Lambda with Python 2020 Skillshare

- Created an AWS API Gateway and lambda back-end with Python.
- Launched an online translation for videos to +8 languages

K&L Consultores Project manager 2016-Present Specialized consulting on Project Management, Safety, and Software Engineering. Designed, innovated, built, and deployed industrial systems.

Developed database for documentation, inventory, and audit processes.

UNIAJC Professor in stem subjects

2016-Present

• Developed +8 STEM subjects for Engineer careers using PBL.

EDUCATION

Full-stack software engineering, Holberton School

2020

• Low-level (C), High-level (Python), Front-end, Back-end & DevOps.

Master degree in math, UTP

2020

Algebra, Analysis, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Stats.

Project management Specialization. Unilibre

• Thesis: improvement of a Project Management Office based on PMBOK

Bachelor's degree in Engineering, UAO

2003

2011

- Graduated **summa cum laude.** Grade: 4.7/5.0.
- Thesis: physics remote laboratory. Java client-server model.